Our very first project in the Self-driving Car Nanodegree will be to find lane markings.
在无人驾驶工程师纳米学位中 我们的第一个项目是寻找车道线
Why is that important?
为什么说这一点非常重要呢？
Well, I can tell you, if you can't find lane markings,
原因很简单 如果找不到车道线
you would have no clue where to drive.
我们就不知道把车往哪里开
You probably don't pay much attention to them,
很多人都容易忽略车道线
but as a self-driving car engineer,
但作为无人驾驶车工程师
it'll becomes your best friend.
车道线是我们最好的朋友
They tell you a lot as to where to drive.
它能提供很多信息 比如行驶的方向
We hear what cloning means,
我们知道克隆这个词语的含义
that our learning problem will copy and clone
无人驾驶车会学习或克隆人类的行为
human behavior so does our steering actions and breaking gas actions.
包括我们的方向盘 刹车 和油门的操作
And you get a chance to try it on your own.
你将有机会亲自进行这方面的尝试
When we train people,
在对他人进行培训时
we don't train them by giving them rules,
我们往往不是直接讲授规则
we train them by letting them learn from examples.
而是通过实例来进行训练
So this unit, you will apply neural networks, deep learning,
在这一单元 你将把神经网络和深度学习技术
to camera images and do some of
应用于所拍摄的图像中
the very things that a self-driving car ought to do right.
并实现无人驾驶车的一些最基本功能
What is computer vision? When you and I drive a car,
什么是计算机视觉？ 当人们驾驶汽车时
we use our eyes more than any other organ to understand what to do.
主要是利用眼睛 而不是其他器官 来判断如何操作
Computer vision, this has the same capability into computers,
计算机视觉则通过摄像头在计算机上实现这一功能
uses cameras and we learn how to extract things like
我们将学习如何从摄像头捕获的图像中
lane markings and other vehicles out of camera images. It's a lot of fun.
提取车道线和其他车辆等信息 这很有意思
I'm now really excited to get you into the world of sensor fusion.
我现在非常兴奋 我们即将进入传感器融合的环节
What is Sensor Fusion?
什么是传感器融合？
It is a science how to integrate different types of sensors.
它是指将来自于不同类型传感器的数据进行整合处理
Self-driving cars have things like lidars and they have radars, and also cameras.
无人驾驶车配备了激光雷达、无线雷达、摄像头 等诸多设备
And, they have internal sensors called gyroscopes inertial measurement units.
此外 它们还配备了名为惯性测量单元 (陀螺仪) 的内部传感器
Sensor Fusion is a science how to come up with
传感器融合利用不同模态的数据
a single coherent picture based on these different modalities.
描绘一幅具有高度一致性的画面
Localization is the simple question,
定位是一个相对比较简单的问题
"Where, relative to the road is a car?"
“车辆处于道路的哪个位置？”
And, it's important because,
这个问题之所以关键
as you're going to see, you got to build maps of the environment.
是因为 如你所见 我们必须对周边环境绘制地图
They have lots of detailed information,
地图包含大量的细节信息
some of which might even be invisible to the robot like,
其中一些信息是计算机所无法感知的
where the danger zones,
比如 哪些是危险区
where do pedestrians typically cross.
哪些是经常有行人穿越的区域
And to make sense of those maps,
我们必须知道这些地图的适用位置和范围
the world must know where is right for the map.
才能让这些地图真正派上用场
And, the alignment of the sensor data the current
此外 还需要将传感器数据指示的车辆当前位置
position to a map, that's what's called localization.
与地图进行匹配 这个过程叫做定位
So now, we entering the fascinating world of what's called controller.
现在 我们即将进入一个称为控制器的奇妙世界
In technical terms, what the controller does,
按照技术术语 控制器指的是
it's a computer program that steers your wheels,
一个可以操控方向盘、油门、刹车
your gas pedal, your break pedal, so as to meet a given objective.
以实现给定目标的计算机程序
So for example, if the objective was to stay centered in the road,
如果你的目标是保持车行驶在道路中央
and you start driving and your car veers to the left,
当你的车向左偏转时
your controller is the unit that decides, "Okay,
控制器会作出决定
we compensate with a slight right turn of the steering wheel."
“把方向盘稍向右打进行校正”
That might sound trivial but it's really easy to screw it up.
这个内容听起来不太重要 却很容易搞砸
Path Planning is the science of how to find
路径规划帮助我们在复杂的路网中
a valid sequence of steps or actions in a maze.
找到一系列按顺序排列的行车步骤或动作
When you gone stuck in Manhattan, for example,
例如 当你想要穿越纽约市
you want to cross this city you,
却在曼哈顿遭遇堵车的时候
have to find a plan,
必须找到一个规划好的路径
a sequence of streets you want to go down to make it all the way to the end.
来告诉你按顺序穿越哪几条街 才能脱离堵车区域到达目的地
A Path Planning algorithm is an algorithm that finds that sequence of actions for you.
路径规划算法可以帮助你找到正确的行车步骤
You can apply it to city navigation.
该算法可以用于城市内的导航
You can also apply it to parking lot navigation,
也可以用于停车场内导航
You will, for example, cross a parking lot.
比如 它可以告诉你如何穿过一个停车场
So now, we are ready for the most fascinating part of this nanodegree,
现在 我们即将进入这个纳米学位项目最激动人心的环节
we will take your code onto a physical car and drive it around in California.
你的代码将会载入一辆真正的无人驾驶车 并将在加州的道路上开一圈
Sounds scary? Yes, I'm slightly scared,
听起来有点吓人？ 是的 我是有点怕
but I'm also really excited because
但我同时也感到非常兴奋
there's no great Nanodegree that would be complete without actually riding,
只有将软件安装到真正的车辆上并在实际道路上行驶
finding actual software on actual cars.
我们的纳米学位课程才算圆满结束 这也是这一课程的与众不同之处
So, let's do it.
让我们开始吧